

Software Engineer

🗣 Shadhinata Sarani, North Badda, Gulshan, Dhaka, Bangladesh 🗯 05 Jan 1996 🏲 Bangladeshi

O Unmarried in radipu → radipu → radipu → radipu → radipu.me

🖒 radipu 🔳 radipu

CAREER OBJECTIVES

I am experienced in leadership and both front-end and back-end programming languages. Now, I am looking for establishing my career as a .NET developer and team lead. I am a quick learner and willing to learn new technologies to upgrade myself with time. I am working with .NET technology since 2018.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Aug 2022 - present Houston, Texas, USA

Gulf State Software

Software Developer 🗷

- Software development, planning, designs, and monitoring of the project development
- Developing web applications.
- Developing WPF applications.
- · Lead a team.
- I worked here with C#.NET Framework, Angular, MSSQL, Azure, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Software Design.

Jan 2022 – Jul 2022 Dhaka, Bangladesh

CureTech Ltd

Software Engineer 🛮

- Developed web applications.
- Worked on the Engineering part of different projects.
- · Lead a team.
- Technologies: C# .NET5, Angular, NodeJS, MSSQL, Laravel, MySQL, AWS, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Software Design

Aug 2021 – Jan 2022 Sunderland, England

Ginilab Limited

Software Engineer

- Worked on Restaurant Management System.
- Added new features, and debugging.
- Technologies: .NET Framework, DevExpress, WinForms, Software Design, Fron-end, and Back-end.

Feb 2021 - Jul 2021

OurEdu

New South Wales,

Software Engineer

Australia

- Developed an Account Management System for the School.
- I was upgrading the old technology to new technology.
- Technologies: C# ASP.NET Core 3.1, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, LINQ, CSS, MSSQL, and DevOps.

Jan 2015 – Jan 2021 Dhaka, Bangladesh

Bangladesh Study Forum (BDSF)

Head of Information and Communication Technology ☑

- Developed the whole IT system for this organization.
- · Lead the IT team.
- What have I done: Website development, Organized programs, public speaking, Leadership.

PROJECTS

Aug 2022 - present

Amedig Management 🛮

Warehouse Management

- Web Application
- Tab App
- iOS App
- Technologies: C#.NET Framework, Angular, MSSQL, Azure, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WPF, Xamarin, and Software Design

Feb 2022 - Jul 2022

Bachao 🗷

Against the rape

- It's a mobile application platform against rape.
- The backend was developed with .NET.
- Technologies: .NET5, Angular, WebAPI, MSSQL

Aug 2021 - Jan 2022

Restaurant Management System

- It's a desktop software, mostly used in the UK and in the middle east.
- Nearly 200+ restaurants and thousands of customers use this software for ordering food inside and outside the restaurant.
- Added new features and debugging.
- Technologies: ASP.NET, DevExpress, WinForms, MySQL, Laragon, HeidiSQL

Feb 2021 - May 2021

Account Management System for Shidlai Ashraf Secondary School

- Enroll new students with details information.
- · Adding new staff and teachers.
- Payroll and tuition fees management.
- Online payment module.
- Technologies: C#, ASP.NET Core 3.1, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS, jQuery, JSON, LINQ, and following Onion Architecture.

Library Management System

Technologies: C#, ASP.NET Core 2.1, Bootstrap, CSS, jQuery, JSON, LINQ.

•	SKILLS
---	--------

Programming

Language C, C++, Java, JavaScript, C#, R, Python,

TypeScript

Backend

NodeJS

Database

Oracle, MySQL, MSSQL Server, PostgreSQL

Source Control

Git, GitHub

Interpersonal skills -

Listening, Caring, Leadership, Self-Motivated, Responsibility, Teamwork

Frontend

VueJS, Angular, HTML5, Bootstrap, CSS3, Sass,

Frameworks

.NET Core, .NET, Laravel

DevOps

AWS, GCP, Azure, Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes,

Bash

Data Structure and -

Algorithm

Cyber Security

Penetration, Forensics, Reverse Engineering,

Social Engineering

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering May 2021

International University of Business Agriculture and Technology Dhaka, Bangladesh

Completed BSc with a CGPA of 3.27 out of 4.00

Jul 2011 - Aug 2013 **Higher Secondary Certificate**

Dhaka, Bangladesh Cambrian College

Completed HSC with a GPA of 5.00 out of 5.00

Secondary School Certificate Jan 2009 - May 2011

Shidlai Ashraf Secondary School Cumilla, Bangladesh

Completed SSC with a GPA of 5.00 out of 5.00

✓ INTERESTS

- Learning New Skills
- Public Speaking
- Reading

Writing

Leadership

♠ LANGUAGES

Bangla **English**